总有一天 你将饮下记忆之泉的水
One day, you will sip from the Fountain of Memory.
到那一天 我们还会再见
When that day comes, we will meet again.
再一次证明了你就是一堆没脑子的傻肉
Time again, you prove to be no more than dead weight.
也许你应该把我
Perhaps you should mark me a traitor,
也当成叛徒宰了
and have me killed as well.
人们会低估你 朱利亚诺
People underestimate you, Giuliano,
而这种观念使你特别适合
Yet that perceived weakness makes you suited,
从暗处抓出间谍
to flushing out a spy from cover.
是你把那些文件放进了我的房间
You're the one that slipped those documents into my quarters.
你变节多久了?
How long have they owned you?
你跟她一样惹人生气!
You are just as exasperating as she was!
- 她死了吗?  - 没什么区别 她离开了
- Is she dead?  - No difference, she's gone.
所以你才不敢直视我 因为她离开你了
That's why you can't stand to look at me because she left you.
- 我看到一个人  - 他是谁 莱昂纳多?
- I saw a man.  - Who was it, Leonardo?
放开我
Free me.
- 你看到了什么?  - 是我自己
- What did you see?  - It was me.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：潇妹纸
时间轴：Leon
翻译：竺 SceneryJuly
校对：竺 影子
达芬奇的恶魔 第一季第6集
这是疯了吗?
Is this madness?
怎么... 怎么可能?
How... how could it be?
在那个洞里...
In that cave...
放开我
Free me.
我还是个孩子...
How could I have seen myself...
怎么可能看到成年的自己?
when I was not yet myself?
在你出生的很久之前 密特拉之子
The sons of Mithras have been entwined with your destiny,
就与你的宿命纠缠在了一起 莱昂纳多
since long before you were born, Leonardo.
时间是一条河流
Time is a river,
而我们中有些成员已经学会了
and there are members of our fraternity who have learned,
顺流而下和逆流而上
to navigate it both upstream and downstream.
你可能会觉得自己还不是自己
You may think that you're not yet yourself.
不过在每一刻 你都既是那个曾经的顽童
But, in every moment, you are both the child you once were,
又是将会成为的圣贤
and the sage you will some day be.
- 这不是答案  - 我从没答应过给你答案
- That's not an answer.  - I never promised you answers.
找答案的话 你要找到叶之书
For those, you will need to find the book of leaves.
牵绊着全人类问题的答案
Answers to questions that haunt all men.
也有你心中问题的答案
Questions that haunt you.
- 我母亲的命运  - 还有更多
- The fate of my mother.  - And more.
我说的是你的命运
I speak of your destiny.
我很欣赏这表演 阁下
Much as I enjoy the entertainment, signor,
我们是来跟公爵讨论雇佣他的佣兵的
we came to talk to the duke about hiring his mercenaries,
不是来看他们毫无意义的斗殴
not to watch them beat each other senseless.
先生们 来点蜂蜜酒吗?
Some mead, fine sirs?
谢谢 对 好的
Thank you. Yes, indeed.
我们加了点蜂蜜
We mull it with a little honey.
乌尔比诺公爵领地的特产
The pride of the duchy of Urbino.
- 一点蜂蜜?  - 别废话 快喝
- A little honey?  - Just fucking drink it.
漂亮! 厉害!
Brilliant! Bravo!
- 美第奇!  - 乌尔比诺!
- Medici!  - Urbino!
你战斗的样子像是一个渴望战斗很久的人
You know you fight like a man who's not seen battle for far too long.
是啊 已经都很多年了
It's been too many years. Yes.
我是费德里科・达・蒙泰费尔特罗 乌尔比诺公爵
Federico Da Montefeltro, Duke of Urbino.
这位是莱昂纳多・达芬奇
Leonardo Da Vinci.
居然在看书? 天啊!
Reading? My!
这本启蒙读物是金泰尔・贝奇给我的
This primer was given to me by Gentile Becchi.
你还在怀念他
You mourn him still.
嫂子 我有什么可以为你效劳的?
How may I serve you, sister-in-law?
过些日子 我们要给马尔泰迪・格拉索举行一场宴会
We are due to hold a pageant for Martedi Grasso, some days hence.
希望你可以陪我
I hoped you might escort me.
就算洛伦佐从外交活动上回来了
Even if Lorenzo returns from his diplomatic forays,
宴会一开始他总是要找些公事去做
he usually finds pressing business when the revels begin.
至少他付了宴会的钱
At least he pays for the revels.
可是我去又有什么用呢?
But what is a lady to do for a partner?
我只能感谢洛伦佐还有个弟弟
I can only thank heaven Lorenzo has a brother,
而且舞技了得
who knows his way around a dance floor.
嗯 请原谅 我还有计划要布置
Mm. You must forgive me, but I have a plot to unravel.
贝奇让我负责查出我们之中的内鬼
Becchi charged me with ferreting out the spy within our midst.
可是证明贝奇是内鬼的证据确凿
But the evidence against Becchi was overwhelming.
事实证明了内鬼的能力
Testament to the ability of our spy.
他是个天才
He is a kind of genius.
那么宴会的时候 我只能一个人了
I will soldier on at the revels without you, then.
我已经被你的奉献精神打动了
I'm touched at your dedication.
事实上 你机遇无限...
The fact that, for all your opportunities...
而却只想做正确的事
you're so intent on doing the right thing.
也许这就是你最有魅力的品质
Maybe your most attractive quality.
夫人 该服药了
My lady, it is time.
我的私刑又到了
My personal torturer has arrived.
- 你知道我们没得选择  - 嗯
- You know we have no choice.  - Mm.
经过早些年的失败 如果我想生个儿子
Twice a day, I must down this potion,
就要每天两次 喝这个方子
if I'm to produce a boy, after my earlier failures.
摩西 告诉朱利亚诺这里都有什么
Oh, Moses, tell Giuliano what's in this.
我自己说不出口
I cannot bring myself to say the words.
驴奶 鹿茸粉
Asses' milk, powdered goats' antlers,
公牛睾丸....
Bull's testicles...
朱利亚诺 你要是能生个儿子
Giuliano, you could spare me this liquid atrocity,
我就不用喝这个了
if you would father a son yourself.
如果我们再不赶紧生个儿子
If we do not produce a male heir soon,
或者没有直系的子嗣降生
somewhere in our line,
美第奇家族将会
the house of Medici will start,
变成不稳定的投资项目
to look like an unstable investment.
我们都有自己的职责 我明白
We each have our duty, I see.
干杯
Salut.
在那里
It's there.
从位置上看这块大陆在西方
Logic dictates that land lies due west.
你觉得只是需要辨别出一个简单的基本方向
You think the identification of a simple cardinal direction,
就可以达到目的?
is all you need to find your goal?
足够让我开始行动了
It's all I need to get started.
你可能得花上百辈子的时间一直向西
You could spend a hundred lifetimes traveling west,
明白吗?
could you not?
阿乌拉罕・本・尤瑟夫带到佛罗伦萨来的地图
The map Avraham Ben Yosef brought to Florence,
不是原始的 只是一张副本
is not an original, but a reproduction,
布满其中的标记只有一个人能够解读
riddled with notations that only one man can decipher.
就是复制它的绘图者
The cartographer who copied it.
- 又是个密特拉之子?  - 他的名字叫所罗门・奥拜
- Another son of mithras?  - His name is Solomon Ogbai.
我们叫他阿比西尼亚人
We call him the abyssinian.
对你来说幸运的是 他还没死
Lucky for you, he is not dead.
暂时还没有
Not yet.
你还可以救他
You have yet to save him.
他在为土耳其苏丹效力的时候
His retinue was brutally intercepted,
被粗暴地劫持了
while he was traveling under the employ of the Ottoman Sultan.
一个野蛮的军阀拿他当做战俘
A most savage warlord holds him captive.
外交手段甚至赎金 都换不回他
The abyssinian cannot be freed by simple diplomacy, or even ransom.
只能依靠你的奸诈和创造性了
It will take guile and inventiveness which only you possess.
很微妙的时刻 我跟佛罗伦萨有委任关系
These are delicate times. I have commitments to Florence.
你的宿命不在佛罗伦萨 莱昂纳多
Your destiny lies elsewhere, Leonardo.
趁阿比西亚人还活着把他救出来
Save the abyssinian while he still breathes.
我必须再考虑考虑 不能...
I have to think it over, I can't...
你已经考虑好了
You've already thought it over.
事实上 你的旅途已经开始
In truth, your journey has already begun.
时间... 是一条河流
Time... is a river.
你已经做出了决定
You have already made the decision.
你每次都会做决定
You make it every time.
他又拿硬币给你演示了 是吧?
He's done the coin thing, has he?
你就是绘图者
You're the map maker.
我还以为你需要解救呢?
I thought you needed rescuing?
- 会的  - 在将来?
- I will.  - In the future?
你越早脱离现在和将来这些词汇
The sooner you move beyond words like present and future,
就越早成为我们想要你成为的人
the sooner you become the man we need you to be.
密特拉之子都不会好好说话吗?
Are all the sons of Mithras unable to speak plainly?
我承认 有时候我们很难理解 不过你也可以
I admit, on occasion, we can be inscrutable, but so can you.
我要在光天化日之下
I wanted to meet the storied Da Vinci,
见到那个传说中的达芬奇
in the bright of day.
一旦鬼门关开启 我们就是不同的人了
We're different men, once hell breaks loose.
什么时候会开启?
And when's that happen?
我们自认为道高一尺
Hell happens when,
而当魔高一丈的时候
the evil of this world exceeds our belief,
灾难就要降临了
that we can conquer it.
你问我你什么时候才能达到那个程度
You ask me when you'll reach that point.
我不能说
I cannot say.
取决于你自己
Depends on you.
不管什么情况降临在我们头上 都不要退缩
Whatever befalls us, do not shirk from the task.
我有创造机会的能力
I have a knack of rising to the occasion,
只要能告诉我是什么样的机会就行...
if I might only be told what the occasion is...
我冒险告诉你
I venture to say it's true,
密特拉之子们在你身上看到的都是真的
what the sons of mithras have seen you in you,
而且你每天都在接近 艺术家
and you are closer every day, artista.
- 接近什么?  - 醒来
- Closer to what?  - Wake up.
你们要带我去哪?
Where are you leading me?
带... 带你? 大师 是你在带路
L... leading you? Maestro, you're the one leading us.
什么?
What?
你半夜叫醒我们 让我们去按照你的吩咐准备东西
You woke us in the night, gave us one of your shopping lists.
买更多的镁粉
Buy more magnesium,
买些东方产不知名的酒精饮料
obtain obscure alcoholic beverages from the east,
三匹马...
acquire three horses...
你有计划的 忘了吗?
You had some plan. Do you not remember?
我有 有 我想起来了
I do, I do. I remember it.
- 我们已经...  - 几天了
- How long have we...  - Days.
这一路上你都生着气
You've been a sullen fuck the entire trip,
就为某个被劫持的外国傻货
all for some foreign halfwit who got himself abducted.
- 阿比西亚人  - 好像...
- The abyssinian.  - It's like...
我好想刚睡醒一样
It's like I'm just waking up.
我在路上丢失了部分自我
I lost part of myself on the journey.
- 去哪里的路上?  - 不是哪里...
- Journey where?  - It's not where...
是何时
it's when.
这个世界的恶魔
The evils of this world.
城堡周围有些奇怪的东西
There's something odd around the castle.
- 这是什么?  - 看看就明白了
- What's this?  - You'll see what it does.
这是谁的领土?
Whose kingdom is this?
当地人叫他斯戴普斯
The locals call him Stepes.
我们来找的就是他?
That's the man we've come to confront?
抓了你要的战俘的是个该死的暴君?
The one who has your captive is the fucking impaler?
我在战斗中瞎了右眼
I lost my right eye in battle.
摘掉鼻梁之后 这样我还能有一些间接视力
Removed the bridge of my nose, so I'd still have peripheral vision.
就这样
There.
很聪明 对吧?
Clever, eh?
很是... 亮眼
That is quite... gleaming.
我们来解释一下来这里的原因吧
And so we should explain our reason for being here.
- 皮耶罗?  - 可以吗?
- Piero?  - May I?
在你我领地之间有两块教皇的土地
The two papal states flank your land and mine,
在我们一只眼睛盯着罗马的时候...
and while we can watch Rome with one eye...
总要用另一只... 呃眼睛
we must always keep another...eye,
盯着北方教皇的土地
always on the pope's property, to the north.
除非...
Unless...
北方领土成为我们的
the northern realm became our property.
要怎么实现呢?
And how would that happen?
哦 如果我们结盟
Well, if we allied ourselves.
佛罗伦萨和乌尔比诺
Florence and Urbino.
我们分割领土之间的教皇土地就成为可能了
It'd make sense if we could carve up the northern papal territory between us.
我可以征服博洛尼亚城和它附属的土地
I can annexe the city of bologna and its environs.
而你可以让自己在亚得里亚海的港口翻倍
You could double your port capacity on the adriatic.
果断一击 不过为什么我不能自己征服这一整片呢?
A bold stroke, but why don't I conquer it myself?
我出人 你出什么?
I have the army. What do you offer up?
当然是出钱
Money, of course,
从全欧洲最大的银行
from the largest banking concern in all of Europe.
从我们每个受到...
From each of us, as he is...
眷顾的人手里
blessed.
吓到你了 是吧?
Scared you, didn't I?
别紧张 美第奇
That'll be fine, Medici.
我不该刺激我的教子的
I shouldn't provoke my own godson,
不过我喜欢考验人
but I like to test a man.
你证明了自己是个值得信任的盟友
You've grown to be a worthy ally.
而且我已经很久没有带人参加过战斗了
And it's been too long since I led my men into combat.
看来 我们的请求非常适时
Our proposal is timely, indeed.
你来找我的时候
I knew you had something juicy in mind,
我就看出你心里有鬼了
when you showed up on my doorstep.
你大老远跑来
There's no way you'd caravan all this distance
肯定不是来看我拉屎的
just to watch me take a shit.
头巾被钉在头骨上
Their turbans are nailed to their skulls.
这都是土耳其人的尸体 显然城堡主人和土耳其打过仗
All Turkish. Clearly this warlord has an issue with the Ottomans.
他勇猛抗击土耳其 最后坐了十三年牢
His bravery against the Turks won him 13 years in prison.
既然我们都不是土耳其人
But, seeing as none of us are Turks ourselves,
就没有什么好担心的了
we should have nothing to fear.
他不会误把我当做土耳其人吧?
You don't think, with my blood, someone could take me for a Turk?
我怎么知道他不会看错人?
How do I know this warlord's eyes aren't failing?
因为我从很远就听见你了
Because I spotted you from miles away.
虽然我失明 但我能听到你们谈话
Though I were blind, I could hear the clattering
从很远就能听见你们鞑靼人在这瞎扯
and nattering of your tartar tongue from further yet.
- 我不是鞑靼人  - 那你是谁?
- I'm not a Tartar.  - What are you, then?
- 一个不同寻常的人  - 不同寻常?
- Unique.  - Unique?
屎壳郎也觉得自己不同寻常啊
Dung beetles think they're unique.
一听你就是混血的杂种
Your mongrel half-breed lineage speaks louder than your words.
上帝用各种手段惩罚人类
You see god, well, has many punishments for mankind.
地震 火山喷发 瘟疫 癌症
Earthquakes, volcanoes, plagues and cancers.
更糟的是 他送来了土耳其和鞑靼人
Worse than these, he sent the Turks and the Tartars
还有你这样的杂种
and the mongrels, like you.
贵安 弗拉德龙骑士之子
Ave, vladislaus Dracula filius,
特兰西瓦尼亚公国王子
Vaivoda partium transalpinarum.
特兰西瓦尼亚和瓦拉几亚公国王子
Prince of Transylvania and Wallachia,
弗拉德二世 名为弗拉・德拉库或弗拉德龙骑士
Son of Vlad II known as Vlad Dracul, or Vlad the Dragon,
您是弗拉德三世 龙骑士之子
which makes you Vlad III, Son of the Dragon.
在您的语言里称为 德拉库拉
Or as it is known in your language, Dracula.
很好 你知道我的爵号
Impressive, your command of my titles,
现在告诉我 你是谁 到这来干什么
but tell me who you are and what you want here.
我是莱昂纳多大师
My name is Maestro Leonardo.
这是我的同伴 尼科和琐罗亚斯德
These are my companions, Nico, Zoroaster.
我们是佛罗伦萨总督
We were sent by the magnificent Lorenzo De Medici
洛伦佐・美第奇派来的
of the Republic of Florence.
全意大利都想知道您是怎样打败土耳其人的
All of Italy wonders at your victories against the Ottomans,
我的领主希望和您交好
and my lord extends his friendship
并请您到佛罗伦萨和瓦拉吉亚公国
and seeks military counsel for the greater glory
做军事顾问
of Florence and Wallachia.
你知道这片土地已经被战争
You must know this land has been bedeviled by war,
折磨得满目疮痍
and worse than war.
我们可以...
We shall talk more...
边吃边谈
at dinner.
但愿他要吃的不是我们
As long as the dinner's not us.
教皇的浴室现在只要购票就可以进来了 是吗?
So we're selling tickets to the papal baths now, are we?
这是件紧急的事
An urgent matter has arisen.
紧急到你都可以让她进来玷污这里吗?
Urgent enough that you sully this chamber with her presence?
我知道在哪能找到妓女 不用你找
I know where to find whores if I want them.
我们觉得你最好直接听她汇报
We thought it best you hear this news directly from her lips.
我刚从佛罗伦萨来 陛下
I've come from Florence, your holiness.
你从城里跑出来...
And does your absence from the city...
不会引起怀疑吗?
create no suspicion?
我在锡耶纳的姑妈会给我找借口脱身
My aunt in Siena is providing me with an alibi.
佛罗伦萨没有政要会惦记我
No-one of import will miss me in Florence.
显然你丈夫不属于那种人
Certainly your husband doesn't fall into the category of import.
洛伦佐的战争工程师最近怎么样?
What of Lorenzo's war engineer,
洛伦佐特别赞赏的那个
in whom the count seems so fascinated?
达芬奇离开了城市
Da Vinci has set out from the city.
没人知道他去了哪里
No man knows where.
女的也不知道?
Nor woman?
我也不知道
Nor I.
洛伦佐本人也离开了佛罗伦萨
Lorenzo himself has left Florence.
现在
As we speak,
他正在会见乌尔比诺公爵
he makes an embassy to the duke of Urbino,
也刚与斐迪南和伊莎贝拉
fresh with the credit of his dealings
达成协议
with Ferdinand and Isabella.
他希望与他们建立新的军事联盟
He seeks to create a new military alliance.
这个深谋远虑的流氓
The calculating rogue.
我们试图削弱洛伦佐的势力
Far from reeling at our attempts to weaken his rule,
可是他却在半岛上召集起了一支
Lorenzo courts the most accomplished mercenaries
训练有素的军队
on the peninsula.
我知道他们的行动是什么
I know what the naval do with them.
他和乌尔比诺将会向北进军
He and Urbino will march north.
一起掠夺我们博洛尼亚的土地
Together, they'll sack our lands surrounding Bologna
然后将其瓜分
and divide them up.
您是怎么知道的 神父?
How do you know, holy father?
因为我也会这样做 你这该死的懦夫
Because it's exactly what I'd do, you fucking coward.
看看你们
Look at the lot of you.
吓得不敢把这消息告诉我
Too scared to bring me this news yourselves.
躲在这个佛罗伦萨淫妇身后
Hiding behind this Florentine slit.
看看我这些手下的怂样
How can I wonder Lorenzo resists me so well,
难怪洛伦佐能轻而易举地抵抗我
when I see the quality of my allies?
我们只想尽力为您效忠
We only tried to serve your glory.
我们没想享受您的神圣指引
We had not the benefit of your divine guidance.
指引? 你想要指引?
Guidance? You want guidance?
还记得上帝选择我的征兆吗?
Do you remember what proved I was chosen by god?
有很... 很多征兆 陛下
So... So many things, your holiness.
我小时候没有被水淹死
The way I survived drowning as a child.
让我看看你怎么样
Let's see how you do.
神父 无疑... 仁慈的上帝会宽恕他的
Holy father, surely... a loving god shows mercy.
你敢质疑我?
You dare question me?
你敢质疑上帝所说的话
The rock upon which god's words stands.
吻这枚戒指
Kiss this ring.
你们毁了我的沐浴
My bath is ruined.
不管你用什么手段 给我干掉美第奇家族
I don't care how, end the House of Medici,
不然我就干掉你
before I end you.
晚宴已备好
Dinner awaits.
我们怎么才能把那人救出来?
How are we supposed to free the captive from a place like this?
要是我知道 我就叫达芬奇了
If I knew that, I'd be Da Vinci.
你把钱扔在地上了
You've dropped some change.
你当然会看到这些钱
Of course, you'll have noticed the money.
苏丹币是东方异教徒使用的...
The sultanis is a base currency...
低劣货币
for the heathen ruler of the East.
这样我的士兵们就能向我
You see, this is how I allow my soldiers
证明他们的忠诚
to prove their loyalty to me.
我把这些苏丹币扔到地上 扔到他们面前
I toss these sultanis on the ground before them.
你知道吗? 这些硬币从未被碰过
And, do you know, the coins are never, ever touched?
胡乱扔这些货币的话
It's just they've fallen quite randomly,
你能听出哪个被捡走了?
you'd really notice if one was gone?
我从不遗漏
I miss nothing.
请坐吧
Please, now.
喝点托斯卡纳酒
A little Tuscan wine,
找找家的感觉 怎么样?
just to make you feel at home, no?
谢谢
Thank you.
您刚从狱中逃出来 却这样热情好客
I must say, I'm impressed with your hospitality,
很让我感动
so soon after your escape from captivity.
因为我习惯了狱中的生活
I am, sadly, at home in dungeons.
小时候 父亲把我的兄弟和我
As a child, my father sent my brother and me
送给土耳其苏丹做人质
to be hostages held by the Turkish sultan.
我的兄弟最终在狱中叛变
The prisons converted my damnable brother
他投降了土耳其 而我没有
to the cause of the Turks, but not me.
我学会了不相信任何人
I learned to trust nobody.
不相信任何人才能在痛苦 恶狗 地牢
To survive any pain, the dogs, the dungeons,
甚至在给我留下
even a lightning strike,
这疤痕的闪电中幸存
which has left me with this... web of scars.
如今我每时每刻都要反抗我的兄弟...
Now I spend every waking hour in resistance to my brother...
和该死的土耳其人
and the fucking Turks.
所有人都认可你的胜利
Well your victories against them have been recognized,
甚至罗马教皇
even by the pope.
如果要干杯
If we're going to raise a toast,
请敬给那个助我逃离监狱的
let's lift a glass to the one who helped me out of the prison this time,
光明使者
to the Bringer of Light himself.
是谁 殿下?
Who, my lord?
路西华 光明的使者
Lucifer, the Bringer of Light.
众天使中最美的一个
Most beautiful of all the angels.
撒旦怎样帮你?
And how did Lucifer help you?
和我一样 路西华反抗暴君
Like me, Lucifer rose against a tyrant.
和我一样 被他所爱的上帝抛弃和背叛
Like me, he was abandoned and betrayed by the god he loved.
我和路西华定下了协议 他将给我自由
I made a pact with Lucifer to win my freedom
并协我最后一次登上王座
and ascend to my throne one last time.
你知道吗?
Do you know?
没有了灵魂 我并不感到痛苦
I don't find it hard to live without a soul.
敬路西华
Lucifer.
怎么那么巧啊
And how fortuitous for Da Vinci.
我刚要来询问问题 这个聪明鬼就出城了
The clever devil leaves just as I arrive with questions.
你不觉得好奇吗?
You don't find that curious?
相信我 先生 这是他最不值得好奇的事
Trust me, signor, that's the least curious thing about him.
你和他什么关系?
What is your relationship with him?
我们好过...
We had our day...
但也就那么一天而已
but that's all it was, a day.
他总是专注于其它的事
And, anyway, his eye is set on another.
- 你怎么知道?  - 我是女人
- How do you know?  - I'm a woman.
我们当然只是朋友
No, of course we're friends.
他救过我一命 所以我很钦佩他
He saved my life and, for that, I deeply admire him.
这并不违法 对吧?
That hasn't become illegal, has it?
影响了佛罗伦萨的安全 那就是违法的
It has if it hurts Florence.
我想让你帮忙保卫佛罗伦萨
All I want is your help in guarding her.
我不知道他去哪了
I don't know where he's gone.
你很为他保守秘密
You keep his confidences well.
我可以和其他人撒谎 阁下
I'd like to lie to anyone else, excellency,
但我不会对你撒谎
but not you.
但是 要是你逼我撒谎的话
Although, if you tried to force it out of me,
我也就没有办法了
I'd be helpless to stop you.
或许我们应该到别处去谈
Perhaps we should discuss this somewhere else.
- 找个更安静的地方?  - 恩
- Somewhere more quiet?  - Mm.
在那里欢闹一下
Until we make it less so.
城门已经关了
The city gates are closed.
离宵禁还有两分钟 混蛋
Two minutes to curfew, scoundrel.
赶紧回家 不然就整夜待在这别走
Either you get your arses home or spend the night here.
谁宵禁后还在街上闲逛 我就把他的名字
Persons caught roaming the streets after curfew get put in my little book.
记到册子上 然后你就得向法官解释了
Being put in my little book means you explain your transgressions to the judge.
美第奇先生 抱歉
Signor Medici, forgive me.
我没看到你和她在一起
I hadn't seen you with a bar wench.
- 你的小册子?  - 我的记录本上面记满了蠢货
- Your little book?  - My ledger, full of pigs, mostly.
每桩违禁你都有记录?
You record every curfew violation?
自从禁令开始以来都有
Since the day it was declared.
所以如果查的话 可以查出有谁在不该出门的时候
If one were to study these, one might see who was out,
私自跑出去吗?
when they shouldn't have been?
没错 然后那个人就要挨罚了
Yes, if one were a glutton for punishment.
给我看看那些册子
Take me to them.
看这些记录可能要花几周的时间
One could speak weeks paging through these records.
那太好了 我兄弟说我最擅长浪费时间
Then we're in luck. According to my brother, I'm great at wasting time.
说说你的秘诀 先生?
Your secret, sir?
噢 知道要混合什么元素就好了
Oh, it's a matter of knowing which elements to blend.
加点镁粉 再加点铁粉之类的
Magnesium here, iron filings there, so on.
我觉得这很有创意
I think it's ingenious.
这个能应用到军事上吗?
Does it have a military application?
还不行
Not yet.
好吧 那我们以后一定还会再谈
Well, then, we must talk further.
自从我放弃基督上帝
Since I've renounced your christian gods,
我就只能用智慧和残暴
I've only my wits and ferocity to protect me
来抗击苏丹穆罕默德二世的军队了
from the forces of Sultan Mehmed II.
或许你给洛伦佐的这个发明
Perhaps the ingenuity you bring to Lorenzo's court
也可以让我受益
could benefit me as well.
现在...
Now...
既然你为我展示了这宴会节目
since you've shown me your little party piece,
我也要展示一下我的小消遣
I will respond in kind with a little diversion of my own.
你看啊 失去了沉重的灵魂
You see, without a soul weighing me down,
我的视线可以穿透黑暗
I can see in the dark.
我无法被杀死
I cannot be killed.
我可以享受一些几年前
I can enjoy certain entertainments
可能会吓得我面色惨白的娱乐节目
that may have made me blanch years ago.
这是土耳其使臣的最后一个随从
This is the last of the retinue of a Turkish ambassador
他愚蠢地试图接近我
who was foolish enough to approach me.
我要让土耳其人记住
I miss no opportunity in reminding the Turks
他们给我的童年
of the childhood they provided.
这是我们要找的那个人吗?
Is it the one we're looking for?
给他松镣
Unshackle him.
现在... 请你证明你比自己那些朋友强
Now... prove stronger than your friends.
打败这两只狗 我就放你自由
Defeat these dogs and you will go free.
别觉得我灭绝人性
And please don't think me so inhuman
连搏斗的机会都不给你
that I wouldn't give you a fighting chance.
给你这把黄油刀
Here's a butter knife.
求求你! 不要!
Please! Don't!
这...
This...
这才是正义
This is justice.
我们可以上主菜了吗?
So... shall we send for the main course?
我吃不下去
I can't eat.
我的口味不是人人都喜欢
My tastes are not universally shared, it's true.
- 我们散席吧  - 在那之前...
- Let us retire.  - Before we do...
您为我们准备了我们家乡的传统酒
you have honored us with the traditional wine of our homeland,
我们也为您准备了传统的瓦拉吉亚酒
and so do we honor you, with the traditional liquor of Wallachia.
- 你买了图伊卡酒?  - 嗯
- You've brought tuica?  - Mm-hm.
我们佛罗伦萨的总督对您表示钦佩
Well, our master in Florence would spare no expense
所以绝不会对您吝啬 殿下
to demonstrate his admiration for you, my lord.
敬弗拉德三世
To Vlad III.
我从没见过你们喝酒也会犹豫啊 朋友?
When have I ever known you to hesitate about a drink, my friend?
敬弗拉德三世
To Vlad III.
好
Good.
给你的仆人也尝一尝吧? 你的随从?
And some for your maid? Your men?
- 好  - 好? 恩
- Yes.  - Yes? Good.
好的
There you go.
你来一点... 你也来一点
Some for you... Some for you.
为这些朋友找个房间
Show the friends to a room.
- 来尝一点  - 等我的随从给客人敬酒之后
- Some for you.  - Once my guards have toasted our guests,
我还有话要和艺术家谈谈
The artisan and I will parley further.
给你的狗也尝尝怎么样? 今天娱乐节目很卖力
How about your dogs, who entertained us so well, this evening?
给你一些 最后一点给你
There's some for you, for you, the last little drop.
请别觉得难受
Please don't be unsettled by the vermin.
我欢迎老鼠
I welcome them.
通常在监狱里 他们是我唯一的朋友
Often, in prison, they were my only friends.
我知道被关在地窖里什么感受
Well, I know what it is to be thrown into a cell.
没有蝙蝠陪伴
Without the companionship of the bats,
我不可能活下来
I would not have survived.
你看
You see.
- 我们能相互理解  - 恩
- We understand each other.  - Hmm.
来吧
Come.
很漂亮 对吧?
Beautiful, is it not?
所以我才那么渴望回到波奈里古堡来
You see, this is why I wanted to return to castle Poenari so badly.
站在这高度...
From the heights...
我几乎可以忘却几十年来
I can almost forget the decades the Turks
那些被关在地牢里的土耳其人
have been living underneath the earth.
很遗憾 刚才那是最后一个土耳其人了
It's a shame, then, that was the last of them.
噢 其实还有一个
Oh, there is one more.
他们的主人所罗门・奥拜
Their master, Solomon Ogbai.
奥拜这个名字
The name Ogbai,
在阿姆哈拉语中 是"别带他走"的意思
In Amharic, it means don't take him away.
是啊
Yeah.
没错
Indeed.
为了报复他们让我卑躬屈膝
For stooping to serve them,
我在这个埃塞俄比亚人身上花了很长时间
I take my time with the Abyssinian.
为了我的兴趣爱好 我把他关了起来
I keep him ready for my personal whims.
我为他发明了新的折磨方式
I invent new ways to torture, just for him.
我把他关在靠窗户的地方
There is a window, near where I keep him.
他看不到窗外
He cannot see the view.
我说要是他能找来...
So I said I would recreate the scenery for him...
制作小模型的材料
if he would only provide me with
我可以为他造出那个景色来
the raw material for a suitable miniature.
这是我窗外那些塔的模型...
These are the crenulations of the towers outside my window...
是用那埃塞俄比亚人的肉刻出来的
carved in the abyssinian's own flesh.
他将永远看不到痛苦的边界
There is one frontier he shall never stop exploring.
痛苦
Agony.
我能和你说句真心话吗?
May I share a confession with you?
当然...
Yeah, yes...
请吧 殿下
if it pleases, my lord.
我知道...
I know...
我疯了
that I'm mad.
确实
Indeed.
但请告诉我 不然我还能怎样?
But will you tell me how I could be otherwise?
父亲把孩子从家里带走
A father rips a child from his home,
夺去孩子熟识的一切
from everything he knows
然后把他扔到自己敌人的手掌中
and tosses him into the claws of his worst enemy.
我们...
Well, we are...
我们的命运通常被父亲决定了
We are too often what our fathers make us.
不管我们是否愿意 是好是坏
Whether we like it or not, better or for worse.
是的
Oh, yes.
我的情况肯定糟糕的
In my case, definitely for worse.
我父亲教给我
You see, my father, he taught me
残酷是全世界的通行货币
that cruelty is the only true currency of the universe,
如今我是基督国家最富有的人了
and now I am the richest man in all of christendom.
哈!
Ha!
- 天啊 你真在这里  - 恩?
- My god, it is true.  - Yes?
仆人告诉我 你抱了一大堆书回来
Servants told me you were carrying books upon books into your quarters.
我还以为他们喝多了
I wondered if they'd been raiding the wine cellar.
- 我很好取笑吗  - 只是有时而已
- I'm easy to tease.  - Only sometimes.
好吧 至少你有自己的爱好
Well, at least you have a hobby you love.
那你这个新爱好是什么?
And what is your new hobby?
佛罗伦萨人爱收藏记录的癖好有回报了
The Florentine obsession with record keeping is paying off.
这些是城里每个守卫 在每个站点的巡逻记录
These are the records to every guard at every station in the city.
无论什么理由 违反宵禁的人都会被记录下来
Anyone who breaks curfew even for a slight reason will be put down here.
包括那个真正的间谍
Including, I suppose, the true spy,
那个诬陷贝奇的人
whom you believe framed Becchi.
没错 可现在还有些问题
You smirk, but there are mysteries to be solved here.
比如 为什么里面有这么多星座的符号?
For example, why do these symbols from the zodiac keep coming up?
这个 我觉得是摩羯座的符号
This. That's the sign for capricorn, I think.
这个是水瓶座 对吧?
And this, that's aquarius, yes?
因为佛罗伦萨的某些贵族比较在意
With certain sensitive subjects of Florence,
自己的名字被列进违反宵禁的名单
their names are indicated with symbols,
所以就用符号代替他们的名字了
rather than list them clearly as violators of the curfew.
啊 这个日期我记得
Ah. This date I recall.
那天参加完整夜酒宴之后 我回家的路上被盘问了
After a long night of carousing, I was questioned on my way home,
所以这个符号代表我吗?
So is this the symbol for me?
因为您是体育冠军
Athletic champion that you are,
射手座的符号再适合您不过
Sagittarius is a natural code name for you.
那快告诉我这些符号都代表谁
Tell us the identity behind each of these symbols, then.
我也不知道这些符号的意思
I'm not privy to that knowledge.
- 这些都在德拉戈奈蒂队长的办公室里  - 给我拿来
- That's in captain Dragonetti's office.  - Obtain it for me.
贝奇会为你感到骄傲的
Becchi would be proud of you.
我们要救的人肯定已经死了
The man we're here to save must be dead by now.
不 还没死
No. No, not yet.
但是... 但是我们必须赶快救他
But... but we must move to save him now.
你们两个去吧
You two can go on.
- 我觉得我可以睡上一周  - 我也是
- I feel like I could sleep for the next week.  - As could I.
那是因为我们中毒了
That's because we've all been poisoned.
什么?
What?
喝点解药
Drink some antidote.
那个混蛋
That bastard.
- 他在我们的酒里下毒  - 不是他
- He slipped something in our drinks.  - No.
是我
I did.
为了你那血腥的追求 你什么事都能做出来
There's nothing you won't do to us in your bloody quest.
我... 我在来之前给图伊卡酒里下了毒
I... I adulterated the Tuica before we arrived.
想让他相信酒是安全的 咱们必须先喝
That we'd all have to drink it, in order to convince him it was safe.
现在...
And now...
所有人 包括两条狗 都应该昏睡过去了
everyone, including the dogs, should be passing out.
准备好了吗?
Ready?
你怎么会认识路?
How do you know where we're going?
我做了简单的建筑结构分析
It's a simple architectural assessment.
那个埃塞俄比亚人用某种方式告诉了我
The Abyssinian pointed it out to me himself in a way.
你想告诉我们是什么方式吗?
Do we wanna know what you mean?
其实你们最好别问
No, actually, you don't.
就是这
It's here.
你确定吗 大师?
Are you sure about this, maestro?
不
No.
写的什么?
What does that say?
不要带我走
Don't take me away.
现在 这才是正义
Now, this, this is justice.
敬弗拉德三世
To Vlad III.
我这个混血的杂种向您道别
Farewell greetings from a half-breed Mongrel.
尼科...
Nico...
去备马 我去外面找你们
go get the horses. I'll meet you outside.
啊 那一根
Ah. That one.
小心 小心 小心
Careful. Careful. Careful.
这一根 然后那一根
It's that one, then that one.
别太快 不然会割得更深
Not too fast, he'll be cut even deeper.
没事了 可以了 都没事了
It's all over. It's OK. It's over.
没有 还没有
It's not. It's not.
那个不是他
It's not him.
不是弗拉德
It's not Vlad.
该死
Shit.
坏了
Fuck me.
你就是个自大的傻瓜 是吧?
You're an arrogant little fool, aren't you?
我免疫所有对人类有害的毒品和药剂
I've endured every drug and poison known to man.
我是从土耳其王国挣脱回来的
I fought off the Ottoman Empire.
你真的以为我会死在一个该死佛罗伦萨人
Do you really think that I would die at the hands,
手里吗?
of a fucking Florentine?
该死
Shit.
或者一个杂种手里吗?
Or a mongrel?
这东西当军事用品怎么样?
How's that for a military application?
琐罗 醒醒!
Zo, wake up!
醒醒! 琐罗!
Wake up! Zo!
生命...
Life...
生命就是个陷阱 你觉得呢?
Life is a trap, don't you think?
现在 我来放你自由
Well, now, I'm going to set you free.
有意思
Curious.
没有灵魂的人你是杀不掉的
You cannot kill a man without a soul.
你必须走
You must go.
不要退缩
Do not shirk from the task.
接下来的几天不要进佛罗伦萨城
Stay out of Florence for the next few days.
哦 而且不要跟洛伦佐说话 跟城里谁也别讲话
Oh, and don't speak with Lorenzo, or anyone in the city.
我觉得我可以去锡耶纳...
I suppose I could go to Siena...
编个故事解释我为什么不在 不过为什么呢?
and create a story to explain my extended absence, but why?
怀疑教廷计划
You've seen what happens,
是什么下场 你见过了吧?
when people question the plans of the Vatican, haven't you?
见过了
I have.
路上不要跟任何人讲话
Speak to nobody along the road.
也确定没人跟你讲话
And make sure no-one speaks with you.
这应该不难
That shouldn't be a problem.
我有办法
I have a strategy.
- 派人跟着她  - 明白
- Have some men follow her.  - Of course.
然后悄悄地杀了她
Then discreetly have her killed.
她对我们已经没有利用价值了
Her value to us has been exhausted.
她...
She's...
已经被自己对达芬奇的感情所影响了
compromised by her affections for Da Vinci.
是教皇命令这么做的吗?
Did his holiness order this?
在接近佛罗伦萨的地方动手
Do it outside the walls of Florence.
不要留下跟罗马有关的线索
Leave no ties to Rome.
布置成土匪杀人越货的样子
Make it look like bandits did it.
哦 还要... 刺穿她的双眼
Oh, and er... have them drive stakes through her eyes.
她看到的太多了
She's seen too much.
守卫 还有狗 就快醒过来了
The guards, the dogs, they're gonna rouse soon.
这伤口是哪来的?
Where did you get that wound?
还有比这重要的事情要解释
There are more urgent things to explain.
- 你知道会这样吗?  - 我知道有可能
- Did you know this would happen?  - I knew it might.
我不得不抓住机会 为了叶之书
I had to take that chance, for the book of leaves.
剑给我
Sword.
大师 我们给他处理一下伤口吗?
Maestro, shall we see to his injuries?
还有更要紧的事 而且我也不能死在这
They're beyond seeing to and I cannot meet my end here.
换句话说 离开这个鬼地方吧
In other words, fuck this place.
我要往弗拉德的尸体上吐口唾沫
I want to spit on Vlad's body.
是 可以 如果能找到在哪就行
Yeah. Well, you could if we knew where it was.
他妈的跑哪去了?
Where the fuck is he?
别管了! 走吧!
Just come on! Let's go!
也许是有什么动物给拖走吃了
Maybe some creature dragged him off.
咱们别管了 走吧
Let's not find out. Come on.
你一定要试试这个 卡米拉
You really must try this, Camilla.
你肯定比你哥哥喜欢甜食
Surely you have a sweeter tooth than your brother.
你的笑都比他甜
You certainly have a sweeter smile.
加点蜂蜜
Some honey.
乌尔比诺公爵领地的特产
The pride of the Duchy of Urbino.
我跟他们的公爵协约了
Oh, I've made arrangements with their duke.
有了他的强援 我真可怜那些妄图侵害佛罗伦萨的人
With rawn like his, I pity those who wish harm upon Florence.
这样你会赚到盆满钵满的
You'll have your hands full with that one.
费德里科・达・蒙泰费尔特罗是个... 很有意思的人
Federico Da Montefeltro's a... colorful character indeed.
- 你邀请我们来是要炫耀新的盟友的吗?  - 伯纳德!
- Did you invite us here to show off your new alliance?  - Bernardo!
巴龙切利先生 我都不记得邀请过你
I don't recall inviting you at all, Signor Baroncelli.
也许你是没理解我去乌尔比诺的原因
Perhaps you fail to understand why I went to Urbino.
你觉得罗马会照顾帕吉家族
You think Rome will look after the Pazzis.
不过 等一切都过去之后
But, when all is said and done,
罗马照顾的只有罗马自己
Rome only looks after Rome.
而你们二位都是佛罗伦萨的皇家子弟
And you both of you are loyal sons of Florence.
你们难道不认为我们自己共和制下结合的时代已经到来了...
Don't you think the time has come for union in our republic...
而不是吃里扒外?
not further divisions?
我弟弟朱利亚诺脑子很笨
My brother Giuliano has a stubborn mind,
不过心肠很好
but a good heart.
某个角度上讲 我们也想让他受到教皇的封赐
At one point, we hoped to see him in a cardinal's hat,
不过以我们目前与教廷的关系行不通了
but our current relations with the church have precluded that.
不过 一个朱利亚诺这样的年轻人 需要未来
And yet, a young man like Giuliano, needs a future.
他应该可以成为卡米拉的好丈夫...
He would make a fine husband for Camilla...
不是吗?
would he not?
还有人要加蜂蜜吗?
Honey, anyone?
再会
Farewell.
再会(意大利语)
Arrivederci.
不管帕吉家族同不同意这次联姻 我都要问
Whether or not the Pazzis agree to this union, I have to ask,
你问过你弟弟这件事情了吗?
did you consult your brother about this?
朱利亚诺的利益就是佛罗伦萨的利益
Giuliano's interests are the interests of Florence.
别担心 我跟他谈之前 会拿走房间里所有易碎品
Don't worry. I'll have breakable objects removed from the room before I broach the topic.
她可是我们敌人的孩子 阁下
She is the child of our enemy, Signor.
会有人认为我们把他送入虎口的
Some might argue he is being thrown to the wolves.
你低估我弟弟了 皮耶罗
You underestimate my brother, Piero.
我们不是割肉饲虎
We are not feeding these wolves.
而是驯虎
We are taming them.
你知道他要提这个事情吗?
Did you know he was going to propose this?
算是有吧...
I had an inkling...
正合我意
seeing as it was my idea.
- 你服药了吗?  - 别紧张
- You've had your elixir?  - Relax.
据说在挫折时怀上的孩子出生都会痛苦
They say children conceived in frustration are born bitter.
你会明白我们周围这些恶魔们已经让我焦虑不安了
You'll understand I'm agitated by this league of devils around us.
经过我们对帕吉家族的计划之后
After our ploy with the Pazzis,
你还没有准备好再一次行动
you're not ready for another master stroke.
医生说这个方子更容易让我们怀上个男孩
Our doctor said this position is more likely to conceive us a male heir.
男人都喜欢把女人的脸压得很低
Men would prefer a position where a woman's face,
低到甚至不能说话的姿势
is rammed down so far she can't even speak.
抱歉 你说什么 亲爱的?
I'm sorry, what was that, dear?
来吧
Please.
喔!
Wooo!
是铁笼
It was the cage.
是铁笼 铁笼割的
It was the cage. It was the cage.
上面写的字说不要带他走
The words written on the don't take him away.
不是讽刺 是警告
It wasn't a taunt, it was a warning.
如果你被救出来 弗拉德制造的这个装置...
Vlad built the device to eviscerate you if you were freed...
就会撕开一条暗伤
to rip an unstanchable wound.
我早该发现的
I should've realized.
- 抱歉  - 没关系
- I'm sorry.  - Never mind.
我必须给你讲讲你要找的钥匙
I must tell you of the key you seek.
打开天穹的另一把钥匙?
The other key that opens the vault of heaven?
对 告诉我
Yes, tell me.
在罗马 等你去拿
It's waiting in Rome, there for your taking.
而且 当你拿到两把钥匙的时候...
And, when you have both keys...
你母亲卡特琳娜
your mother, Caterina.
她还活着
She is alive.
她为我们带着叶之书
She carries the book of leaves for us,
在我地图里那块大陆上...
beneath the post of the sun in a town made of stone...
石头小镇的太阳之柱下
in a land on my map.
为什么... 我需要你给我解释地图
Why... I need you to decode the map.
那你就要拿走你需要的
Then you may take what you need.
在这
Here.
这就是能破译地图的秘密
Here is the secret to deciphering the map.
我不可能活着跟你走
I will not survive to come with you.
等我死了你必须把它割下来...
You must cut my flesh loose and take it with you...
带走
once I die.
那个土耳其人说我可以解救你
The turk said that I would save you.
而且你会的...
And so you will...
某一天...
someday...
不过不是今天
but not today.
但之前你还有很多事情要学
But there are so many things you must learn first.
是吗? 什么?
Yes? Yes?
你要学会一切皆有可能...
You must learn that anything is possible...
包括失败
including defeat.
- 你要... 学会...  - 什么? 什么?
- You must... learn...  - What? What?
什么?
What?
- 什么? 什么?  - 大师...
- What? What?  - Maestro...
- 我要学会什么?  - 大师 他死了
- I must must learn what?  - Maestro, he's gone.
- 大师  - 我要学会什么?
- Maestro.  - I must learn what?
我要学会...
I must learn...
该死! 该死! 该死!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
该死! 该死
Fuck! Fuck.
我来过这
I've been here before.
- 没有 这不是我们来的路  - 不 不是那个意思
- No, this isn't the path we came in on.  - No. No.
这是我跟阿比西亚人第一次见面的地方
This is where the Abyssinian and I first met.
他警告我...
He warned me...
我觉得可以解决问题...
I thought I could solve things...
如往常一样
like I always do.
我们自认为道高一尺...
Hell happens...
而当魔高一丈的时候
when the evil of the world exceeds our belief,
灾难就要降临了
that we can conquer it.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：潇妹纸
时间轴：Leon
翻译：竺 SceneryJuly
校对：竺 影子